### Contact

669-300-8346 (Mobile) shubhamrajvanshi9@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ shubhamrajvanshi (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Cloud Computing Java Kubernetes

### Languages

English (Professional Working)
Punjabi (Limited Working)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

ITIL 2011 Foundation Certificate MCTS Windows Server Active Directory, Configuring Oracle 9i SQL CKAD: Certified Kubernetes

Application Developer

# Shubham Rajvanshi

Software Engineer at Cisco

San Jose

## Summary

Problem Solver, team player and quick learner, working as Software Engineer for Cisco's Hybrid Cloud solution Cisco CloudCenter Suite with interest in Cloud Native Computing, DevOps, Big Data, Virtualization and Linux.

Hands on experience in developing, deploying and managing CNCF applications in Kubernetes, Amazon Web Services, Azure, Google Cloud, GKE, VMware, Openstack.

Knowledgeable in other technologies and Virtual Infrastructure Java API, Docker, Zookeeper, Kafka, Hadoop, Node.js, Reactjs, Windows Server 2008, Powershell, PowerCli, Oracle 9i SQL.

I prefer Java, Nodejs & Python as my programming languages, MySQL and MongoDB as SQL/NoSQL databases and have keen interest in learning Golang.

I have ITIL 2011(F) and Oracle 9i SQL certifications.

# Experience

Cisco

4 years 9 months

Software Engineer

February 2019 - Present (1 year 11 months)

San Jose

- Mentored Cisco CloudCenter hands on lab in Cisco Live, San Diego- Jun 2019.
- Implemented API's to consume data from Confluence Kafka REST Proxy using Golang for Cisco Intersight - SaaS Systems Management Platform microservices.
- Implemented a Mock Kafka Rest microservice to be used for Dev & Stage testing using Golang & Gorilla Mux framework.

- Developed tool used by Cisco Customers to migrate their Data and Application Deployments from CloudCenter version 4.10 (Monolithic) to 5.X (Cloud Native-Kubernetes). Used Java & Spring framework to create and consume REST API's that serve data for migration.
- Implemented CI/CD Jenkins pipeline for GitHub pull requests.
- Developed cloud native apps using Nodejs, MongoDB for the Test Automation team for Kubernetes deployment testing.
- Successfully installed Linux & Kubernetes servers on VMware, OpenStack, Amazon EC2, Amazon EKS, Google Cloud Platform, Google Kubernetes Engine, Azure, Azure Kubernetes Service.

Software QA Engineer October 2016 - September 2019 (3 years)

San Jose

Worked as Software Engineer in Test and includes below jobs and responsibilities:

Work closely with engineers, business owners, and customer service professionals throughout the development and testing lifecycle, including the requirements gathering and design

Documentation and creation of Test cases for new features using Testrail and Confluence.

Bug Tracking using tools like JIRA, Rally.

Triaging, Troubleshooting, Debugging and deploying bug fixes at end user staging and production systems.

Integration testing with third party internal and external tools like Cisco ACI, UCSD, ServiceNow etc

Develop tests using Python and Shell Scripts in a Linux environment, document and coordinate the deployment of manual and automated tests for complex distributed and microservice

based systems.

Test execution and validation in both public and private clouds like Amazon Web Services (AWS),

Azure, GCP, GKE, Openstack, VMware vSphere and vCloud Director.

Customer Support Engineer April 2016 - September 2016 (6 months) San Jose

Conduct technical troubleshooting sessions with customers working closely with Sustenance team, help with development of internal and customer

facing documentation and help triage and document bugs and enhancements requests as seen in the field.

Build and deploy docker based images and containers for in-house testing and deployment in AWS, Openstack and VMware. Developed applications and services to be deployed by CliQr platform.

Deploy and Manage Tomcat based application on linux servers hosted on AWS, Azure, Openstack and VMware.

CliQr Technologies Now part of Cisco Software Engineer June 2015 - April 2016 (11 months) Santa Clara

Conduct technical troubleshooting sessions with customers working closely with Sustenance team, help with development of internal and customer facing documentation and help triage and document bugs and enhancements requests as seen in the field.

Build and deploy docker based images and containers for in-house testing and deployment in AWS, Openstack and VMware. Developed applications and services to be deployed by CliQr platform.

Deploy and Manage Tomcat based application on linux servers hosted on AWS, Azure, Openstack and VMware.

San Jose State University ITIL Practitioner and Instructional Student Assistant October 2014 - June 2015 (9 months)

San Jose

 Worked at University's ITS department under User Experience and IT Projects. Job & responsibilities involved:

Implementation of ITIL services within ITS departments.

Project Coordinator for Digital Signs Project which involves deploying Digital Screens that can be centrally managed from a remote location.

 Apart from this I also worked as an Instructional Student Assistant under Dr. Simon Shim for subject CMPE 283 Virtualization Technologies. My job function involved managing and configuring VMware ESXi (5.0, 5.5) based virtualization lab for students. Worked with Dr. Shim in introducing Docker and PowerCli as a part of course curriculum. Tata Consultancy Services Systems Engineer May 2011 - January 2014 (2 years 9 months) Bengaluru Area, India

- Worked on installation & deployment of Price Waterhouse Coopers Windows 2003, 2008, and Vmware ESXi global Infrastructure.
- Provided Platform Admin support for more than 6000 servers on a daily basis.
- Managed DNS records & Windows Active Directory using PowerShell.
- Handled troubleshooting tickets & Change Requests following ITIL processes.
- Provided access to PWC resources for its users including server access.
- Participated in in-house DR activities, coordinating with the cross-functional teams for its success.

Frontline Consulting Services (FCS) Inc Intern

July 2008 - November 2008 (5 months)

Hyderabad, India

As an Intern, I worked on ETL based tools like Oracle Warehouse Builder and Oracle BI and used them to develop a Sales Database using the company's entire sales data. This data came from various sources like excel Files, databases, etc. Used PL/SQL procedures and functions to refine the data extraction using the tool.

## Education

San Jose State University

Master's Degree, Software Engineering · (2014 - 2015)

Punjab Technical University
Bachelor's Degree, Information & Technology · (2005 - 2009)